<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[hungry academy]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.hungryacademy.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.hungryacademy.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-06T15:52:53-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.hungryacademy.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Hungry Academy]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hungry Academy: One Month In]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hungryacademy.com/blog/2012/04/06/hungry-academy-one-month-in/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-06T15:52:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hungryacademy.com/blog/2012/04/06/hungry-academy-one-month-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One month ago, 24 of us walked into the glass double doors on our floor in LivingSocial HQ. We didn’t know each other, and while some people had done a fair amount of work in Ruby, Rails, and other programming languages, some of us were complete beginners. What a difference a month makes!</p>

<p>At times, Hungry Academy feels like a mini-conference. We have fantastic speakers coming in each week, giving us the ins and outs of what they are working on and how they do what they do (And we’ll try to keep up on posting about some of them so you all can enjoy too!). Sometimes the conversations are internal to LivingSocial and the tools they use, but more often they are peeks into the larger world of Ruby and Rails – the world that we already seem to be a part of.</p>

<p>We’ve worked on three major projects so far, all of them in Ruby. It’s amazing when we pause and look back at what we’ve done, especially for those of us who weren’t programmers at the start. Concepts that seemed impossible at the beginning of March now make sense. We built an event manager to do extract, translate, and load processes. We built an EventReporter that extended those concepts. And then we built a relational ‘database’ essentially from scratch – setting us up for the next project on our plate.</p>

<p>Coming at us hard and fast: Rails. Our first project is a doozy: building the creatively dubbed ‘StoreEngine’. It’s got a list of products. It’s got a shopping cart. It’s got administrators and users. It’s got transactions. Authentication. Authorization. As one of us put it, “It’s a big project – but when it’s done we’ll have a very good idea of what Rails does”. So if you have a friend in Hungry Academy, don’t be surprised when they dig in and turn down invitations to go play for a few weeks. And if you’re following along, get ready. This one is fun.</p>

<p>One month down. Four to go!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Power of Community]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hungryacademy.com/blog/2012/04/06/the-power-of-community/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-06T15:05:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hungryacademy.com/blog/2012/04/06/the-power-of-community</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Most people’s mental image of the typical computer programmer is less than appetizing. He (or possibly she) is an overweight, glasses-wearing nerd who hacks away in his or her basement and finds more comfort in their computer then in other people. It’s a shame that such a stereotype exists, as it discourages those who might be interested in programming from making the leap.</p>

<p>As is often the case, the truth is vastly different than what people think when looking in from the outside. These so-called “antisocial nerds” quietly built one of the most active, enthusiastic, and robust communities I’ve ever seen. And that community does not exist solely in the world of bits and bytes.</p>

<p>There is great strength in healthy communities. They fulfill our desire for human interaction and provide motivation, inspiration, and education for their members. These ideas are not groundbreaking, but it is worthwhile to show how these principles played out in the Hungry Academy community during our latest project: Sales Engine.</p>

<h2>Motivation</h2>

<p>A major aspect of programming is dealing with constant frustration. If you have no one around to keep you focused, the temptation to throw in the towel comes sooner than most of us care to admit. At Hungry Academy, we work harder and longer than we have before because we are surrounded by others who are doing the same. It is not uncommon for  us to regularly put in 10 to 15 hour days to meet a project deadline – and these are projects for ‘class’, not for any real-world client or job.</p>

<h2>Inspiration</h2>

<p>Sales Engine required us to break into pairs for partner programming, which meant that 12 different teams were building their own version of the project. We rolled our own relational database and published a gem that allows a user to make specific queries on that database. The beauty of having 12 groups tackle the problem is that we had 12 different implementations. Discussions between groups on how they approached specific problems allowed us to gain new insight into tackling similar problems in our own projects, or similar problems in the future. Seeing the simplicity, power, and elegance of another group’s well-written code inspired us to write code that was not only functional, but beautiful as well.</p>

<h2>Education</h2>

<p>Working in pairs allowed us to learn from each other. Not only did we gain insight into how other programmers approach and solve problems, we also had to explain our solutions to our team members in a way they would understand. If you can teach someone else a new concept, you are well on your way to mastering it yourself. It’s a little paradoxical, perhaps – but if your desire is to be the best student, you also need to be the best teacher.</p>

<p>Those of us in Hungry Academy have made amazing leaps in our learning and development in the last month, and all that hard work was made palatable – and fun – because of the community LivingSocial and Jumpstart Lab fostered. If you’re interested in programming, know you don’t have to hack it alone! Find a local meetup, or join many of the online communities – it will be much easier to master the language, and you’ll have more fun doing it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jesse &amp; Improv]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hungryacademy.com/blog/2012/03/16/jesse-and-improv/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-16T16:09:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hungryacademy.com/blog/2012/03/16/jesse-and-improv</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Improv for All!</h2>

<p>Take a moment, if you will, to imagine the following scenario.</p>

<p>You walk into a room - concrete floors, white walls, modern looking chairs and desks. Surrounding you are 23 mostly 20-something individuals. You know that you&#8217;ve all been selected, or chosen, or hired, or picked - everyone is in the room for a reason. A few faces are familiar, but you don&#8217;t really know anyone - and for the next five months you&#8217;ll be spending most your waking hours working side by side.</p>

<p>What&#8217;s your first reaction? Would you be yourself from the first second? Or would you pull back a little, keep things contained and professional rather than genuine?</p>

<p>It happens all the time in classrooms across the country. Students who know little to nothing about each other file in and sit down and learn from their teachers. Eventually they learn about each other - who is fast, who is hilarious, and who _____. But learning is an exercise practiced by individuals - not an activity performed as a team.</p>

<p>Surprising fact: The first day at Hungry Academy, none of us touched the command line. No one opened up a text editor or tried to understand the basics of Ruby. Our first day was all about Improv.</p>

<p>Improv is about being comfortable in a group. It&#8217;s about letting that genuine, wacky, creative person show through a little. And the magic of a team comes when it&#8217;s members are comfortable enough to let the wacky come through.</p>

<p>Leading us in our improv journey was Jessie Sternshus, founder of <a href="http://www.improveffect.com/">The Improv Effect</a>. In less than 48 hours, she took a group of friendly strangers and created a team. People who know each others&#8217; names, but more importantly know each others&#8217; personalities. We know that certain people are killer at organizing things or people. We know who in a group setting is more likely to aggressively start throwing out ideas and who is more comfortable letting the ideas flow for a while and then adding some really great concepts when things quiet down.</p>

<p>Most importantly, we learned that it is OK to fail so long as you learn from the failure. We learned that inside our Hungry Academy team, people won&#8217;t snicker or judge if we say something nonsensical. That the words &#8220;I don&#8217;t understand&#8221; won&#8217;t mark us as unitelligent or bad students or strange people. After all, after you&#8217;ve passed sounds and movements around a circle in a full-body version of Telephone it&#8217;s pretty clear that we&#8217;re all a little strange. And that&#8217;s not a bad thing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Week]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hungryacademy.com/blog/2012/03/16/first-week/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-16T16:08:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hungryacademy.com/blog/2012/03/16/first-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The lead-up to Hungry Academy was exciting to say the least.  Emails flew from one coast to the other filled with getting-to-know-you facts, advice the best areas of the District for intrepid apartment-searchers, and hopes and thoughts on Hungry Academy itself.  It was a time filled with what would most aptly be described as &#8220;unbridled enthusiasm&#8221;.</p>

<p>After orientation, we hopped straight into two days of hand holding and group meditation.</p>

<p> Just kidding, it was improv based team building exercises.  Groan if you like, but it was fun  - and helpful!  In a crowd of 23 new faces, it was a great way to get to know each other.  Otherwise it would have been 6 months of &#8220;Dude, can you help me with this?&#8221;, &#8220;nice work, Ace&#8221;, and &#8220;Hey Monster-Man, can you teach me how to dougie?&#8221;.  Jessie Shternshus deserves a lot of credit for forging 26 individuals into a team in less than 48 hours.</p>

<p>With a solid team foundation under-foot, we rolled up our sleeves and took a peek under the hood of Ruby. Here&#8217;s the rundown:</p>

<h3>Step 1:</h3>

<p>Get our feet wet with a walk through of Jeff&#8217;s intro tutorial: <a href="http://tutorials.jumpstartlab.com/projects/ruby_in_100_minutes.html">Ruby in 100 minutes</a></p>

<h3>Step 2:</h3>

<p>Take the basics and apply that knowledge to something a bit more real world.  Enter: <a href="http://tutorials.jumpstartlab.com/projects/eventmanager.html">Event Manager</a>.  Here we learned what a mess data can become.  So, we cleaned it up and got everything into a standardized format.  Pretty awesome for the first week!</p>

<h3>Step 3:</h3>

<p>Annoy everyone you know on <a href="http://www.twitter.com">Twitter</a>!  Why use a dummy account when you can spam real people with<a href="http://tutorials.jumpstartlab.com/projects/jstwitter.html"> JSTwitter</a>?</p>

<p>There it is.  We&#8217;re a few days in, and we&#8217;re already creating programs that have real world applications.  All in all, it&#8217;s been an awesome week and we&#8217;re excited to dig into the next project: <a href="http://tutorials.jumpstartlab.com/projects/event_reporter.html">Event Reporter</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the new HungryAcademy.com]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.hungryacademy.com/blog/2012/03/02/welcome-to-the-new-hungryacademy-dot-com/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-02T16:42:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.hungryacademy.com/blog/2012/03/02/welcome-to-the-new-hungryacademy-dot-com</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When we announced Hungry Academy we promised to follow a model of open
education. We&#8217;d publish our curriculum, tutorials, projects, and
calendar.</p>

<p>This is the fulfillment of that promise. <a href="http://hungryacademy.com">HungryAcademy.com</a> will be the
hub for our activity. In the navigation above you find links to our
writings, calendar, and discussion forum. We expect these collections
and resources to change dramatically over the next few weeks as we
figure out what works and what doesn&#8217;t.</p>

<p>If you want to become a developer, we invite you to follow along,
participate in our community, and learn to build amazing software.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
